<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><?xml-stylesheet type="text/css" href="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/code/pfs.css"?><TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>To the Parliament of the Comon-Wealth [sic] of England. Fifty nine particulars laid down for the regulating things, and the taking away of oppressing laws, and oppressors, and to ease the oppressed. / By G.F.</title>
            <author>Fox, George, 1624-1691.</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 45KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 12 1-bit group-IV TIFF page images.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2016-02">2016-02 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">B23168</idno><idno type="EEBO-CITATION">99883322</idno>
  <idno type="VID">193548</idno>
  <idno type="EEBO-PROQUEST">2240888771</idno>
  
            <idno type="STC">Wing F1958</idno>
            <idno type="STC">Interim Tract Supplement Guide 855.f.3[54]</idno>
            <idno type="STC">ESTC R203676</idno>
            <idno type="PROQUEST">ocm99883322</idno>
            <availability><p>This keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above is co-owned by the
    institutions providing financial support to the Early English Books Online Text Creation
    Partnership. This text is available for reuse, according to the terms of <ref target="https://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/"> Creative Commons 0 1.0 Universal
    licence</ref>. The text can be copied, modified, distributed and performed, even for commercial
    purposes, all without asking permission.</p></availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online text creation partnership.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt><relatedItem type="facs" target="https://data.historicaltexts.jisc.ac.uk/view?pubId=eebo-99883322e"/>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. B23168)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 193548)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Early English books; Tract supplement ; B9:1([58])</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>To the Parliament of the Comon-Wealth [sic] of England. Fifty nine particulars laid down for the regulating things, and the taking away of oppressing laws, and oppressors, and to ease the oppressed. / By G.F.</title>
                  <author>Fox, George, 1624-1691.</author>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>23, [1] p.   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>printed for Thomas Simmons, at the Bull and Mouth near Aldersgate,</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>London :</pubPlace>
                  <date>1659.</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>G.F. = George Fox.</note>
                  <note>Reproduction of original in the British Library.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,363 texts created during Phase 1 of the project have been released into the public domain as of 1 January 2015. Anyone can now take and use these texts for their own purposes, but we respectfully request that due credit and attribution is given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Full documentation of the original data capture process is available from the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.
   All versions of the texts are now archived and freely available for download. See <ref target="https://textcreationpartnership.org/faq/#faq05">the TCP Download FAQ</ref>
   for detailed information. The TEI P5 versions are also freely available from the <ref target="https://github.com/textcreationpartnership">TCP Github repository</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp" matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)" replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term type="topical_term">Society of Friends --  Doctrines --  Early works to 1800.</term>
               <term type="geographic_name">Great Britain --  Politics and government --  1649-1660 --  Early works to 1800.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2014-01 </date>
            <label>SPi Global</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images </change>
         <change>
            <date>2014-03 </date>
            <label>Kate Allen </label>Sampled and proofread </change>
         <change>
            <date>2014-03 </date>
            <label>Kate Allen</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited </change>
         <change>
            <date>2015-03 </date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion </change>
      <change><date>2021-05 </date><label>lb</label>TEI P5 conversion </change></revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <front>
         <div type="title_page">
            <pb facs="tcp:193548:1"/>
            <p>TO THE PARLIAMENT OF THE COMON-WEALTH OF <hi>ENGLAND.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>Fifty nine Particulars laid down for the Regulating things, and the taking away of Oppressing Laws, and Oppressors, and to ease the Op<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pressed.</p>
            <p>By <hi>G. F.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>
               <hi>LONDON,</hi> Printed for <hi>Thomas Simmons,</hi> at the <hi>Bull</hi> and <hi>Mouth</hi> near <hi>Aldersgate,</hi> 1659.</p>
         </div>
      </front>
      <body>
         <div type="regulations">
            <pb facs="tcp:193548:2"/>
            <pb n="3" facs="tcp:193548:2"/>
            <opener>
               <salute>
                  <hi>FRIENDS,</hi> Who are the Parliament of this Common-Wealth, who are to regulate things for the taking away of oppressing Lawes, and oppressors, and to stop the oppressors.</salute>
            </opener>
            <p n="1">1 LET no man be prisoned for Tithes, which have been set up by the Apostates (the Papists) since the dayes of the Apostles.</p>
            <p n="2">2 Let no mans goods be spoiled, and made Havock on Treble, by the Priests and their company, though the Priest doth them no work whose goods he spoils.</p>
            <p n="3">3 Let no men or women be summoned up two hundred miles or upward to the Court at <hi>London,</hi> because they can<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>not give the Priest Tithes, who doth no work for them, and when they appeared they will prison them, because they did not appear by an Attorney, and swear to their answers.</p>
            <p n="4">4 Let no man be prisoned for not appearing by an At<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>torney, who hath appeared in his own person, who is not sick nor beyond Sea.</p>
            <p n="5">5 Let nothing be put in Bills that are more then the thing is, and let nothing be put in Writs more then the thing is, and let nothing be put in Indictments more then the thing is.</p>
            <p n="6">6 Let no man speak in an unknown tongue.</p>
            <p n="7">7 Let no man be prisoned for non doffing his hat, let no man unable, un-man and weaken himself about that.</p>
            <p n="8">8 Let no man be prisoned because he swears not at all, not by Heaven nor by earth, nor by book nor any other oath, but abides in the Doctrine of Christ, and keeps to yea and nay, and keeps his commands who witnesses the end of all strife.</p>
            <p n="9">
               <pb n="4" facs="tcp:193548:3"/>9 Let no man be fined, and his goods spoiled, because for conscience sake towards Christ and his commands hee cannot swear, let no man be put out of place or office, or service because he cannot swear, because he doth what he doth faithful to God, at yea and nay to serve in his place where he is.</p>
            <p n="10">10 Let no man be put out of place for saying <hi>thee</hi> to a par<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ticular, and <hi>you</hi> to many who acts in the singular and plu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ral, let no one be put out of place or office for not doffing their hats, who take not, nor give not the honour below, but to the higher Power their soul is subject, who receives the honour that comes down from above; so let no one be per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>secuted for wearing their hats, for saying THOU, for not swearing, who for conscience sake towards God cannot swear.</p>
            <p n="11">11 Let none have their goods strained and spoiled, and made havock on, and cast into prison for not paying Clerks wages for turning the hour-glasse, and saying Amen, and such like services.</p>
            <p n="12">12 Let no one be put to death for cattel, for money or any outward thing, let them restore, and minde the Law of God which is equity and measurable, agreeable to the of<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fence, and minde the Judges of Old, and <hi>Moses,</hi> and their judgement, (let the thief live to restore for his theft) and minde the Apostles doctrine, let him that stole, steal no more, but work with his hands the thing that is good; So that neither <hi>Moses</hi> nor the Apostles saith, <hi>hang him.</hi>
            </p>
            <p n="13">13 Let no one have their goods spoiled and made havock on because they cannot pay to mend the old Steeple-houses which were the old Masse-houses, who have left their places, and their seats both, and the man that is in it; and for them that be in it, they are uncharitable, though they have left their seats, and left them their house, to take their goods, and make them to maintain it that be come out of it</p>
            <p n="14">14 Let all laws in <hi>England</hi> be brought into a known tongue, that every Countryman may plead his own cause, without Attorney or Counsellour, or for mony, but men that fears God, and hates covetousnesse, decide and end
<pb n="5" facs="tcp:193548:3"/> things among People in all places, but let none do it for money and reward, let it never be had in esteem among you, and away with cap-men, and coyf-men, (as they are called) and thirty shillings, and twenty shillings, and ten groat fees, and this oppression, that makes people pay eight pence a sheet, for not above sixteen lines; So away with all these Councellors, that will not tell men the Law, a few words, without twenty, or ten, or thirty shillings, which is a great oppression.</p>
            <p n="15">15 Let all these things be taken away, that will not speak a few words to people, without money to his neigh<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bour, freely without any end, or reward, or bribery, and so bring it to a free Nation, and so a free People by the pow- of God, and this will be the way to take off oppression off the poor people, when in every place such as fear God, and hate covetousnesse, decides things among the people, and if they be great things, let them send them up to you the Par<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>liament; and away with those lawyers, twenty shilling Councellors, thirty shilling Sergeants, ten groat Attour<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nies, that will throw men into Prison for a thing of nought, for not swearing, for not appearing by an Attorney, for not doffing their hats; so if this trade were thrown away, and making Merchandize of Law, and great soms of money for councelling, and great rewards and fees, and the Priests making a trade of the Scriptures, people would soon come to be plain, and Countrey people would soon decide their businesse, being left to all to do it freely, this would be the way to take off oppression, and if any would speak concern<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing law or Scripture to do it freely, this is the way to bring the Nation like a Garden, and a free Nation, a free people.</p>
            <p n="16">16 Let none that is high, proud, or lofty, envious or scornful bear Office, for he will turn the sword backward, and do the Divels work, which is to bring the World into a Wildernesse, and quench the spirit of God, whereby eve<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ry one should see his way, and he will not be like <hi>Moses,</hi> who said, <hi>would all the Lords People were Prophets; Moses</hi> said so that comprehended all transgression, the first transgression,
<pb n="6" facs="tcp:193548:4"/> and what was transgressed, which sprung forth, for they that are hasty, and heady, proud in a mad blind zeal will turn the sword against the just, and are not a praise to them that do well, such are not a terrour to evil doers, but lets them upon the righteous, and such God will overturn, and overturn, as often as they get up; <hi>Cain</hi> that Governour who built a City, he was called a vagabond, who killed faithfull <hi>Abel,</hi> and he that did so, had not an habitation in God.</p>
            <p n="17">17 And let all fines and amercements be given to the poor, and let no one be prisoned, and fined, and their goods spoiled for not going to Steeple-houses, as many have been; and let no one be imprisoned for going to Steeple-houses, as many have been for speaking a few words to the people, biding them fear God, and repent, and cry<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing up Christ among them, and speaking as they were mo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ved, as it was revealed to them, according to the Apostles doctrine and order, as 2 <hi>Cor.</hi> 14.30. which was the practice and order in the Church of God, that if any thing was re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vealed to another, the first was to hold his peace, but this order is broken amongst the Christians, and they are pri<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>soned till death that practice it, or whipt, or stocked, or imprisoned.</p>
            <p n="18">18 Let no law be, but that man may ask man a question, either going to or coming from Steeple-house, or there, if it be a free Nation, let it be free, let none have the name of a Minister, but such as are able to satisfie all doubts, and all questions, and for to convince, and stop the mouths of all gainsayers, and opposers, and not let them be such as call to the Magistrates to send to prison for asking a question, like the <hi>Jewes</hi> that cryed out, help men of <hi>Israel,</hi> for these are the men that turn the World up-side down.</p>
            <p n="19">19 Let all names of people be thrown down, nick-names that be given for their opinions by men, that all may be ga<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>thered into the Name of Christ.</p>
            <p n="20">20 Now if you say, that we call your Ministers Priests, we do so, from your law, your great law book calls them so, and then their practise shewes it.</p>
            <p n="21">
               <pb n="7" facs="tcp:193548:4"/>21 And let no man be whipped, or stocked, or impri<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>soned, as many have been, for bidding people repent in a market, and to lay aside their deceitful Merchandize, and their couzening and cheating, and swearing, and cur<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>sing, and to keep to yea and nay in all their communi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cations.</p>
            <p n="22">22 Let no man be prisoned, and their money taken a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>way, for going to visit prisoners, and to relieve them in what they wanted.</p>
            <p n="23">23 Let none have their horses and goods spoiled and ta<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ken away, for meeting together in the fear of God, the first day of the week, traveling to meetings.</p>
            <p n="24">24 Let no one that meet together in the fear of God, in se<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>veral houses, waiting upon the Lord, praying, or exhorting, &amp; edifying one another in the most holy faith, let them not have their houses broken, their windows broken, and they pulled out of their houses, and knockt down and beat, and houses unthatched, and many pulled down, and men pluck<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed out, and knocked down, as many have been.</p>
            <p n="25">25 Let none be persecuted and prisoned as vagabonds who are moved of the Lord to speak abroad his Word freely and faithfully, let them not be persecuted as vagabonds, for those are the vagabonds that be envious and wrathful, that turns against the faithful ones, and though they be Lords of Cities, like their old brother <hi>Cain,</hi> yet they are in <hi>Cains</hi> way that turns against the just, and God hath no respect to their sacrifice, though they may build cities, yet vagabonds, if they be envious, that hath not a habitation in God; But <hi>Abel, Abraham</hi> and Christ was not, which were as strangers, and had no certain dwelling house, and Christ had no where to lay his head.</p>
            <p n="26">26 And let none be Goalers that are drunkards, or swea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rers, or oppressors of people, but such as may be good pa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>terns to the prisoners, and let none lie long in Goal, for that is the way to spoil people, and to make more thieves, for there they learn wickednesse together; and let no pee<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vish man bear any office, or ambitious, for he will be exal<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ted with the rich, and a shame to the poor, and not hear
<pb n="8" facs="tcp:193548:5"/> his cause. The cap is on as the rich go with the rich, but the cap off with the poor, and there is the offence, if it be not to the rich; so let not that be minded, but let e<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>very one do justly to his neighbour without respect.</p>
            <p n="27">27 Let no swearer, nor curser, nor drunkard bear any office whatsoever, or be put in any place, nor drunkard nor adulterer, nor covetous Idolater.</p>
            <p n="28">28 Let all this money, and stipends, and Tithes, and hour glasses for preaching by the hour be taken away from men, who make a trade of the Scripture, but let every one speak freely as they have received, but let them go out to get vine-yards, and plant vineyards, and thresh, and plow in hope, and then there will be little cause to call to the Magistrates to give them maintenance, but they will then all have enough, then every one of them will gather into the barn, of the wheat and crop of God.</p>
            <p n="29">29 Let all those Abie-lands, Gleab-lands, that is given to the Priests, be given to the poor of the Nation, and let all the great houses, Abbies, Steeple-houses, and White-Hall be for Alms-houses (or some other use then what they are) for all the blind and lame to be there, and not to go begging up and down the streets.</p>
            <p n="30">30 And let all that worship God, worship him in spirit &amp; in truth, &amp; not tyed up to will-worships, let all those Schools &amp; Colledges down, who makes Ministers by the will of man, but that all may come to wait upon God and Christ Jesus, whereby they are made Ministers by his will, that redeems people out of the earth, but those keep people in the earth, and let not the mouth be stopped, which the Lord o<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pens.</p>
            <p n="31">31 Let all those crosses upon seals be pulled off, and off the silver, and gold, and weights, and of Steeple-houses, and chimnies, and Ships, and signs, and Mayses, and arms, and scucheons, and flags, and Ensignes, and standards which is the Popes Crosse, let it be rooted out of the Nati<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on, and the Pope and his authority.</p>
            <p n="32">32 Let all those Fines that belong to Lords of Mannors be given to the poor people, for Lords have enough.</p>
            <pb n="9" facs="tcp:193548:5"/>
            <p>Now the people of the World that comes into our meet<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ings, spit upon us, throw stones at us, set and throw dogs at us, speak all manner of evil upon us, and all man<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ner of slander, Them that be great Professors and great talkers practice this, and pluckers down, yet if our friend go into the Steeple-house, and aske but a question, they will hale him out, and cast him into prison, or if he speak never a word, they will cast him into prison, and if he do not go, they will cast into prison for asking a question.</p>
            <p n="33">33 Let all the poor people, blinde and lame, and cree<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ples be provided for in the Nation, that there might not be a begger in <hi>England</hi> nor <hi>Englands</hi> Dominions, that you may say you come to be equal with the Jewes, that had the law, that made provision for widows, strangers and fatherlesse, and <hi>Levis</hi> hee that turns his ears from hearing the poor, turns his ears from the Law, which is to provide for them, for ye have read the practice of the Church, the Saints which were in the Gospel, which doth condemn this Na<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tions practice, where is so many Beggars among them, both the Jews in the Law, and the Church in the Gospel? And so let all great gifts given to great men, be given to the poor, let the receiver deny it, and the giver return it to the poor; for the rich may give to the rich, but the poor cannot give it him again, so minde Christs Doctrine.</p>
            <p n="34">34 Let all those Easter-reckonings, Midsommer-dues, be taken &amp; thrown aside, and let no ones goods be spoiled, who for conscience sake cannot give the Priest these things, and let all this Burying the dead for mony, and Marrying for mony, and Christening for mony, and Churching of women for mony, let all these things be swept away, and let the Nation be a free Nation, and what any one doth, let them do it freely; These twenty shilling Sermons, and ten shilling Sermons, and ten groats the grave for the Priest be laid aside, and then see whose mouth the Lord will o<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pen; for mony choaks, and gifts blindes.</p>
            <p n="35">35 And let no man bear the sword that does violence to any man, or accuse any man falsely.</p>
            <p n="36">36 Let all these naming of dayes, those Sunsdayes, and
<pb n="10" facs="tcp:193548:6"/> Moonsdayes, Tuisdayes, Wodensdayes, Thorsdayes, Fry<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dayes, Saturdayes, that is after the Heathens manner (and naming) be put out of your Almanacks, which is contra<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ry to the Jewes naming of dayes, and the true Christians both.</p>
            <p n="37">37 Let all this observing of holidayes, and Saints days, (which hath been set up by them who were out of the pow<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>er of God, as Michalmas, and Candlemas, and Christmas, Whitsontide, Easter, and many of the Saints days which they were killed on, those they feast on, sottish people feast on, fools and Ideots feast on; let this abomination be taken away.</p>
            <p n="38">38 Let no man that is a striker or fighter, and a wrestler with flesh and blood, and wrestles with the Creatures of God, that goes under the name of a Minister of Christ, not to go under the name of Minister, that would have Creaturs to be whipt, stockt and prisoned, for they that fight with powers of darknesse, and spiritual wickednesse, they must lay aside the outward sword and the spear, the whips, the stockings, and the prisonings, and they must come to the spiritual weapons, the spirit of God in themselves, the spi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ritual weapon that wars with the powers of darknesse, and spiritual wickednesse, to bring the Creature into the liber<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ty of the Sons of God, for they that fight with Creatures fight with outward weapons.</p>
            <p n="39">39 Let no Judge, nor Justice, nor Sherif that is ambiti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ous, High-minded, bear rule, or bear any Government, for such are out of the fear of God which is the beginning of wisdom, with which they should order the Creation to the Glory of God the Creator, and are out of the meek state and the humility, and of doing justly, loving mercy, and walking humbly before God, and they are an ill favour in the nostrils of God, and to all sober, tender people and sincere.</p>
            <p n="40">40 And let the noise of this summing people up by writs, into the courts of the Nation and Sessions for Priests, poor people, them the Priest does no work for, let that be ta<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ken away and stopt, and all those Courts pulled down,
<pb n="11" facs="tcp:193548:6"/> that doth oppress and hold up oppression, that Justice might be done without oppression, and not for money, for these things hath shamed the so called Ministers of the Gospel, which sues people up and down, which they do no work for, and so do not bring glad tidings to the Nations, but trouble, as their fruits have declared; What trouble are men brought into by their Courts and Sessions whom they do no work for? had the Apostle done so, he might have made the Gospel loathsom, troublesom, but he kept it without charge; but such there hath been but few since the dayes of the Apostles, so let the Gospel be kept without charge, and let them that Minister the Gospel, keep it with<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>out charge.</p>
            <p n="41">41 And away with all these stipend-men and glebe-land men, augmentation men, gifts, fees and rewards, &amp;c.</p>
            <p n="42">42 Let no man, Priest nor Lawyer have Tithes, augmen<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tations, stipends, glebe-lands, great fees, gifts and re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>wards, but if any one will preach or read the Law, let him do it freely, for God is a free God, and so are his people, and Christ is a free Christ, and offered himself freely; what any one hath received freely from him, he is to give it freely, (this is Christs Command to be obeyed) and so this will be the way to set the Spirit of God free, and the Oxes mouth shall not be muzeled that treads out the Corn, and this will be the way to stop all such that makes a trade of the Law, and Scriptures, that if any one will read Law or Scriptures, let him do it freely, and not by this carnal measure, the hour-glass, by which the Spirit of God is quenched in others, which reveals something to them for edification and comforting, according to the Order and Practise of the Church of God, 1 <hi>Corinthians</hi> 14.30.</p>
            <p n="43">43 And you that are Officers, that have great estates of your own, and Commanders, and men of Authority, do that which you do freely, and that will be the way for to gain the love of God and your Countrey, and the way to take off this oppression, and it will be the way that the poor might have the more plenty, and it will be the way
<pb n="12" facs="tcp:193548:7"/> whereby Justice, the Gospel may run freely without mo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ney and without price.</p>
            <p n="44">44 Let all these things for money, and preaching for money, and singing for money be laid aside, let not preach<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing be a trade, nor the Word of God made Merchandize of; and let not the Law be sold nor bought, and let not them handle the Law, nor none of them be handlers of the Law that will not do Justice without money; for those will not do Justice, but will favour the rich for a fee, a gift or reward, which eates up the poor, and hold people in long suites, by which cause the Just suffers, and is often overthrown.</p>
            <p n="45">45 Let all Images and Pictures be taken away and pluc<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ked up, and blotted out of all Signes, Steeple-houses and Gardens, and Houses, and rooted out of the Land.</p>
            <p n="46">46 And let none keep Ale-houses or Taverns, but who fear God, that is come into the Wisdom of God, that will not let the Creatures of God be destroyed by Drunkards.</p>
            <p n="47">47 Let all Games, Sports be taken away that pleases the fleshly mind.</p>
            <q>Is it not to honour a Magistrate to live in the Power of God?</q>
            <p n="48">48 Let all the Stage-playes, May-Games, Shoffel-boards, Dice, Cards, Nine-holes, Foot-balls and Hand-balls, and Fidlings, and all these vain Musicks, which stirs up the light vain minds of people, that doth not know what to eat nor drink, nor what to put on; let all these things be taken away that stirs up the light mind, and maketh provision for the flesh, or else they will lye upon you.</p>
            <p n="49">49 Let all those Bul-baitings, Cock-fightings, Horse-racing, which is destructive to the Creatures, and to please peoples vain light minds, and is destructive to seriousness; let all these things be taken away.</p>
            <p n="50">50 Let no one wear Sword, Dagger or Pistol, or weapon, but who is in Office, or Service, or Place, and this will bee the way to stop wickedness, and murderers and killers.</p>
            <p n="51">51 Let no man keep Ale-houses or Taverns that keeps
<pb n="13" facs="tcp:193548:7"/> Bowls, Shoffelboard-Tables, or Fidlers, or Dice, or Cards.</p>
            <p n="52">52 Let neither Beggar nor Blind people, nor Fatherless, nor Widows, nor Cripples go a Begging up and down the streets, but that a House may be provided for them all, and meat, that there may be never a Beggar among you; and let this great Fees of Goalers and Garnish-money be taken away, which through those great Fees many have layn long in Prison.</p>
            <p n="53">53 Let all Goals be in wholesom places, that the Priso<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ners may not lye in their own dung, and Piss, and straw like Chaffe, having never a House-of-office in the Prison; Therefore let there be an House-of-office in all Goals, and let these things be mended.</p>
            <p n="54">54 And let all these jangling of Bells cease, which do feed peoples pleasures and vain minds.</p>
            <p n="55">55 Let all those Ballad-singers, and Ballad-makers, and Jest-book-makers which stirs up peoples vain and light minds, be taken away.</p>
            <p n="56">56 And let all this wearing of gold Lace, and costly at<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tire, more like Anticks then sober men, let this be ended, and cloath the naked, and feed the hungry with the super<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fluity; And turn not your ear from the cry of the poor, for if you do, you turn it away from the Law that provides for them.</p>
            <p n="57">57 Let all the Priests restore to the poor people, who have so expressively taken away their goods, treble and treble; if you be the men that will do justice, make them to restore to them their goods again; and that is but Just.</p>
            <p n="58">58 And let not the Priests strike (our Friends, nor set on their Professors and hearers; but keep the Peace.</p>
            <p n="59">59 Let none have their goods taken away for not paying for the Priests bread and wine, their Communion (as they call it) though they do not eat with them, nor hath not for these many years; yet the Church-wardens (so called distrains the goods of our Friends, to make them pay for their bread and wine, their Communion (so called) which they eat and drink.</p>
            <pb n="14" facs="tcp:193548:8"/>
            <p>Justice and Righteousness exalteth a Nation; But sin is a shame both to Rulers and people.</p>
            <q>
               <hi>Be not high-minded but fear, and be meek and low, for the fear of the Lord is the instruction of wisdom, and before honour goeth humility,</hi>
               <bibl>Prov. 15.33.</bibl>
            </q>
         </div>
         <div type="text">
            <p>HE that persecutes another for his Faith, maketh ship<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>wrack of his own in himself; he that persecutes and kills another about sacrifice is a Vagabond, and is <hi>
                  <gap reason="illegible" resp="#murp" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>ain</hi> and not <hi>Abel,</hi> though he build a City, and be the Chief Ma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gistrate in a City, as <hi>Cain</hi> was, and he doth not well, so he hath not dominion over sin.</p>
            <p>He that persecutes another about meats and drinks, and dayes, is in the wisdom below, and out of Christ the substance by whom all things was made, who is the Wis<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dom of God. He that is a Lord over another mans Faith, is a persecutor, and knows not Christ the Lord, the Author of Faith, and God the giver of it; and he that would bear rule over another mans Faith is out of the Apostles Doctrine, 2 <hi>Cor.</hi> 1.24. And he that would bear rule over another mans Faith, will persecute, such will not have him to bear rule over their Faith which Christ is the Au<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>thor of, and so to make shipwrack of Faith, and Christ the Author of it, such doth, as will be Lords, and this is but the form of godliness out of the power, who brings the World on heaps; and this hath been in whole Chri<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>stendom since the dayes of the Apostles.</p>
            <p>Such as would have dominion over mens Faith was the Anti-christs doctrine, and false Christ, which would have been as Christ, who was the author of true the Faith, and these have been making Faith almost in every age, and have power over the false faith, and called defenders of the Faith, and so have wildernessed people, and brought them all into Sects and heaps, and this hath kept people from the power of God: And who comes to receive the
<pb n="15" facs="tcp:193548:8"/> end of their Faith, they receive the Salvation of their Souls. And they that will have the power over mens Faith, they must needs be the end of their faith, which is a dead one; Now they that have gotten power over mens Faith, which is but a dead one since the dayes of the Apostles, for they that be in the living Faith suffereth with Christ, the Author and end of it, before they will yield to others, that would have power over their Faith, which if they get power, they make shipwrack, if not, they persecute the Creature, till death by imprisonment or banishment, whipping, stocking, persecuting and stoning, mocking or reproaching, yea, for their own maintenance such as they do not work for; so those men; Ministers or Teachers, that would have power over mens Faith, and call themselves de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fenders of it, they must needs be the end of it, that have power over it; And now with their power they will perse<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cute and Prison Creatures till death, about their faith.</p>
            <p>Them that seek to have preheminence over mens Faith, which is the cause and ground of bringing all people on heaps and sects in the whole Christendom, for when they have lost the head Christ, who is the Author of the Faith which is one in whom it ends, who hath the power over it; now Christ that hath power over Faith, is the Author of it, and the end of it, he comes to save mens lives, and de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>stroyes the Devil and his workes, and death wherein he hath his Authority, and saves mens lives, and can recon<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cile them to God: And the Apostles that bid people be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lieve in Christ, and look unto him who is the Author of their Faith, and that they should have Faith in Christ Je<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>sus, they wrestled not with flesh and blood, but spiritual wickedness, and rulers of darkness, and brought the crea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tur into the liberty of the Sons of God.</p>
            <p>So men that have power over mens Faith, the dead faith, they destroy the Creatures and mars them, and that is the power of darkness, that leads them to persecute and do the works of darkness, but Christ who hath power over the living Faith, who is the Author of it, the end of it, the finisher of it, he destroyes the Devil the power of dark<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ness,
<pb n="16" facs="tcp:193548:9"/> that went out of truth, &amp; leads men out of truth into the darkness, where they devour one another by that power of darkness, — and Christ is the cause of the living Faith, who saves mens lives, and destroyes the Author of sin, and death, and dead Faith, and the cause and the Author of this Faith, and men destroying one another; so the Devil is the power of death, that went out from truth, where he hath his dead faith, and makes the World like a Wilderness, where death and destruction talkes of the fame of God, Christ, the Prophets and Apostles, where the Devil will have power over their Faith, that murder and persecute Creatures with all his false apostles and false magistrates, which the true Magistrates never did with carnal weapons, with sword and spear, he fights with Creatures, with flesh and blood, he cannot fight with spiritual wickedness, and the powers of darkness, with swords and spears, he that fights with them, fights with flesh, and blood with the Creatures, he doth not preach the Gospel to that which is captivated with the powers of darkness, he that runs against the Creatures with swords and spears, and defaces and marrs it, doth not go the way to bring it into the liberty of the Sons of God, for hee that wrestles with spiritual wickedness and rulers of dark<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ness, he must be turned from them in his own particular, and with that eye he sees the Gospel &amp; receives the Gospel, which is the power of God, and comes to receive the Co<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>venant of Light, whereby the prisoners shewes themselves sorth out of the pit, wherein there hath been no water, and so comes to fight with spiritual weapons and rulers of darkness; for he that fights with the powers of darkness and rulers of darkness, he must have the shield of Faith, and spiritual weapons to beat them down, and to bring the Creature into the liberty of the Sons of God.</p>
            <p>Now they that fight with their spiritual weapons, they come into the true zeal of Christ, and fight not with flesh and blood, to wrestle with Creatures, but fights with their spiritual weapons, and wrestles against spiritual wickedness, and rulers in darkness.</p>
            <pb n="17" facs="tcp:193548:9"/>
            <p>Now they that say, They are Ministers of Christ and Mi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nisters of the Gospel, and Christians, and fight with car<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nal weapons, swords and spears, about your Church, Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ligion and Worship, and Faith and Gospel, those fight with Creatures, with flesh and blood in the mad blind zeal, and are presumptuous and usurped authority, but you cannot sight with outward spear and sword, with powers of darkness, and spiritual wickedness; Now they that fight with spiritual wickedness and Rulers of darkness, they can do no good with an outward sword and outward spear, they can do no good with those weapons, for tha<gap reason="illegible" resp="#murp" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> is <hi>Goliah<gap reason="illegible" resp="#murp" extent="2 letters">
                     <desc>••</desc>
                  </gap>;</hi> but they that fight with that must be with spi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ritual weapons, and lay aside the carnal weapons, sword and spear.</p>
            <p>He that will be Lord over a mans Faith is in darkness, and out of the power of God, and hath lost the head, Christ the Author of Faith, and is in the dead Faith, and doth not believe that he shall overcome sin, and the body of sin, while he is upon the earth.</p>
            <p>He that will persecute men about the Worship of God, he is out of the truth, and out of the Spirit, a will-wor<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>shipper, and in fained humility; for they that Worship God in the Spirit and in the Truth, they are in the Truth that the Devil, and murtherer, and persecutor is out of.</p>
            <p>They that will persecute about Religion, they are in the vain religion below, among whom the power is not over their tongues, who will destroy the Creatures, and perse<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cute to death about their vain religion; but who is in the pure Religion which is from above, that keeps unspotted from the World, which is to visit the fatherless, feed the hungry, cloath the naked, these be the preservers of the Creation; but they that persecute about their vain reli<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gion, be full of the World, and pleading about their bo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dy of sin while they are upon the earth, which cloaths not the naked, feeds not the hungry, relieves not the wi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dow and the sick that lyes up and down like to famish; And such be in the divelish envious persecuting nature, and yet they will profess the Scriptures from <hi>Genesis</hi> to the
<pb n="18" facs="tcp:193548:10"/>
               <hi>Revelation,</hi> where they find not their example, that will persecute people about the Gospel; such be out of the A<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>postles Doctrine, and Christs Doctrine, who wrestled not with flesh and blood, but with powers of darkness, and spiritual wickednesses, &amp; Christ came to save mens lives, not to destroy them, and to bring the Creature into the liber<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ty of the Sons of God, and they that persecute people a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bout the Gospel, are out of the power of God, in the Devils power, which power of God comprehends the World, and all transgression, and is glad tidings which sets free, through which power, life and immortality comes to light, and doth not persecute, and they that persecute people, and burn people, and Prison people about their zeal of Christ, the Prophets and Apostles words, they are mad and blind, and out of the life of Christ and the Apostles, and his zeal that saved mens lives, and brought the Creature into the liberty of the Sons of God, and wrestled with the powers of darkness and spiri<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tual wickednesses, and destroyed the Devil and his works, and death where he had his authority, and reconciled the Creature, and man to God; This was Christs zeal, and did not persecute creatures, but the blind and mad zeal destroyes Creatures, and Prisons and persecutes them to death, instead of reconciling them, that is the Devils power.</p>
            <p>And they that persecute people about Religion, perse<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cute Creatures, and fight with them with swords, spears, staves and bills, <hi>Judas</hi> guard, Prisons, houses of Corre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ction, whipping, stocking, with outward weapons, they quench the Spirit of God in themselves, and throws away spiritual weapons, and such never begets to God, nor Mi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nisters to the Spirit, but sowes to the flesh, that of the flesh corruption may be reaped (and so much of it is to be reaped in Christendom) that is the fruit of the carnal wea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>poned men, which quenches the Spirit, and throwes away the spiritual weapons.</p>
            <p>And who persecute and Prison them about their wisdom and knowledge, opinion and judgement, they have in
<pb n="19" facs="tcp:193548:10"/> Christs, the Apostles and Prophets Words, that will kill, prison, stock and whip with the wisdom which they have in Christs, the Prophets and Apostles Words, such are in the wisdom below that is earthly, sensual and devilish, and out of the Wisdom that is from above, that is not departed from evil, and is not come to it, which is pure and gentle, and peaceable, and easie to be intreated, which doth not destroy but preserve, and is not earthly, sensual nor dive<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lish, for that is destroying.</p>
            <p>They that persecute and kill people about their Church and Ministry, be in the Dragons and Beasts, &amp; great Whores authority, and false church compelling, out of the Domi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nion and Authority of the Church of God (which Christ is the head of) and the Ministry saves mens lives; And that Church which Christ is the head of, who Worship God in Spirit and truth, the Church which is the Ground and Pillar of truth, that all persecutors are out of, for the Devil and all his guard is out of this Church.</p>
            <p>They that say, they are believers which are not born of God, and do not believe in the Light which doth enligh<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ten every man that cometh into the World, and are not born of God, by which they overcome the World; That belief is false, that say, they do believe, and yet while they be upon the earth, they must have a body of sin and cor<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ruption while they be upon this side of the grave, their Faith <gap reason="illegible" resp="#murp" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap> dead, and so their Conscience is defiled; for the Mystery of Faith is held in a pure Conscience, which is a li<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ving lively Faith, that gives victory, through which Faith the fiery darts of Satan is quenched, through which Faith they have access to God that purifies the heart, which the Mystery of is held in a pure Conscience, by which the Just lives, by which they overcome the unjust, the author of death, and the dead faith.</p>
            <p>They that say, they are Worshippers of God, and lives out of truth, they worship as the Devil doth out of truth; for who worships God in the truth, is in that which the Devil is out of, and Worships in that.</p>
            <p>And they that say, they are Worshippers of God, and
<pb n="20" facs="tcp:193548:11"/> must have sin and corruption, and the body of sin while they be upon the earth; they are the will-worshippers, and worships out of the Spirit, and quenches the Spirit of God in themselves, which mortifies sin, and puts off the body of sin and corruptions, through which Spirit they have Unity with God, and one with another, and Scrip<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ture, and them that gave it forth, which was in the Spirit of God.</p>
            <p>They that say, they have a hope, and they must not be pure while upon the earth, which doth not purifie them as God is pure, but they must have sin and corruption, and the body of sin while this side of the grave; it is the hope of the Hypocrite which shall perish, though they do profess all Scripture, from <hi>Genesis</hi> to the <hi>Revelation,</hi> for the true hope, Christ the Mystery, which remains and doth not perish, perfects, and makes as pure as God is pure; and this differs from the false hope which doth not purifie, and is to perish.</p>
            <p>And they that will persecute about hope, be in the Hy<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pocrites hope (like Pharisees) professing Scriptures, and will turn against Christ the hope; and so they persecute him in his Saints. (Why persecutest thou me?) And so they who persecute people about Worship, be out of the truth; for who be in the truth, be in that the Devil is out of, the persecutor.</p>
            <p>They that will persecute People about Faith, be in the dead faith, and is out of that Faith which works by love, and give victory, and quenches the fiery darts of the wic<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ked, the Devil who is the author of persecution.</p>
            <p>And they that will persecute enemies, and hate enemies, and will call them Blasphemers, seducers, they are haters of Creaters, and strikers of Creatures, and hath that pow<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>er which captivates Creatures, and are not the Spiritual men in the armour of God, to sight with spiritual wick<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ednesse, of whom remains the curse that comes not up to fight against the Mighty; The Dragon, and all carnal weaponed men, with which he fights with all about worship; And they that have enemies, have thrown aside the com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mands of Christ, which is to love enemies, and be out of
<pb n="21" facs="tcp:193548:11"/> the love of Christ, and God that loved the World though it lay in Wickednesse, and sent his onely begotten Son into the World, and gave him for an offering, and a sacrifice for the sins of the whole World, and doth enlighten every man that cometh into the World, that all through him might believe, and he that believes him and receives him, hath power to become the Son of God, and he that doth not believe, but hates the light with which he is enlight<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ened, which comes from Christ, he an is Anti-christ, and will not come to the light, because it doth reprove him, and this is his condemnation, who loves the darknesse, rather then the light, because his deeds be evil; and those that call themselves Ministers of Christ, and Preachers of the Go<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>spel, and will persecute men for Tythes, Easter-reckonings, Mi<gap reason="illegible" resp="#murp" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>summer dues, and for Clerks wages for saying Amen, and for not mending the old Mass-house, they be out of the Apostles order and Christ; for no such things were practised among the Ministers nor Apostles of Christ, nor had they any such practice, but stood in the power of God, with which they stopped the mouths of such evil beasts, and slow-b<gap reason="illegible" resp="#murp" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>llies, which taught for filthy lucres sake, which they gave the name of evil Beasts, and slow-Bellies, whose words was as canker, who admired mens persons because of ad<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vantage, who are found in <hi>Balaims</hi> way, <hi>Corahs</hi> and <hi>Cains</hi> way, and persecuting and turning against the just; who will persecute people about the Scriptures, be out of the life of the Apostles and Christ who was the end of the Scriptures, and just mens spirits that gave them forth, in him they end whose name is called the word of God, who is come to fulfill the words of God; for the Ministers of Christ never persecuted any, neither did Christ give them any such com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mand, but taught to love enemies; and so these say they are Ministers of Christ and the Gospel, and teacheth Magi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>strates to persecute, which are contrary to them, have thrown away the commands of Christ and his Doctrine, and are out of the Apostles life and Doctrine both, that be strikers, that sayes they must not be strikers, and out of the mind and spirit of Christ, life and power, who comes to
<pb n="22" facs="tcp:193548:12"/> save mens lives, and judged and rebuked their zeal, who would have mens lives destroyed, and told them they should perish, who would have mens lives destroyed except they repented.</p>
            <p>And they that will persecute people for wearing their hats, are in the honour below, out of the honour that commeth from God above; the hat honour, worship &amp; humility hath been set up in the fall, hath been since man transgressed, &amp; was driven from God, and is the worship among th<gap reason="illegible" resp="#murp" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>m that is covered, but not with the spirit of God, in whom the wit<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ness is transgressed, and quenched; And they that will per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>secute people about that they call civility, &amp; fellowship, and language, and fashions, be out of the fellowship of God, the spirit, and out of the shape of God, and out of the sound speech and language that cannot be condemned, and out of the singular and plural, though they have learned such words amongst themselves, yet practiseth them nor them<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>selves, nor will have others; and the civility stands not in outward things, but in that which comprehends out<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ward things, in which their is love, life, and faith that works by love, who envies not, So the civility in which there is envy, outward civility, but it stands in the love of the World, self-love, honours, self-righteousnesse, w<gap reason="illegible" resp="#murp" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap>l-wor<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ship, fained humility, crouching, scraping, capping, fain<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed love, in which is the envy that have it not, in which is that they call their civility, which is come up since the spi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rit hath been transgressed, in which love and wisdom of God, there is courteousnesse, and kindnesse, and tender<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nesse, and stooping and coming down to the Prisoned and oppressed, and among the captivated ones, here is tender<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nesse, and love, and compassion, and mercy, and the wis<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dom that is from above, in this stands the civility that is plain and pure and good in the love of God, that envies no creature, that would have all creatures to worship God, and honour Him, this love thinks no evil, and this is not of the World, and they are the false Church, and false A<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>postles, and Ministers of unrighteousnesse, and false teach<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ers, and among whom is not the order of the true Church,
<pb n="23" facs="tcp:193548:12"/> nor exhorting, nor edifying; that is, if any thing be re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vealed to another that sits by, the first is to hold his peace, ye may all prophecy one by one, that all may learn, and all be comforted, which was the order of the true Church, and true Ministry; but the false Church and Ministry gets to the powers of the earth, to make them a law, if any one speak to them to bid them hold their peace that sits by, there is something revealed unto them to comfort and edifie the people, the false Church and the false Ministers tells the Magistrates, Revelation is ceased, of whom they have a Law to cast them into prison or house of correction, or getting mony when they are going to the Steeple-house, or in it, or coming from it, as disturbers; And this is the practice of the true Church, which was to edifie &amp; to com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fort, is become disturbers of the false Church and Ministery, that have gotten a law to hinder exhorting and comfort<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing.</p>
            <closer>
               <signed>G. F.</signed>
            </closer>
         </div>
         <trailer>THE END.</trailer>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>